About

Research scientist working at the intersection of machine learning and control theory.

Have 10+ years of experience collaborating with small teams to analyze problems, construct solutions, and effectively communicate the results to stakeholders. Excels at synthesizing and distilling complex concepts/scenarios into easily understandable forms and rapidly acquiring new skills and knowledge.

Work

Yahoo!, Senior Research Scientist, 12/2023 - Present.

Yahoo!, Research Scientist, 7/2022 – 12/2023.

- Lead of team responsible for control algorithm for bidding in real-time ad auctions.
- Designed and implemented changes leading to a 19% improvement in advertiser ROI.
- Rebuilt institutional knowledge of the algorithm's legacy Java code base.
- Overseeing and directing software enginners simplifying the code base.
- Led implementation of an ML-based cold-start prediction of the price control signal.

ACADEMIC HISTORY

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, Assistant Professor, 8/2016 – 8/2021.

Stanford University, Postdoctoral Fellow, 8/2013 – 8/2016.

Institute for Advanced Study, Member, 8/2014 – 8/2015.

ACADEMIC SUMMARY

Published 10 papers (400+ citations) in geometry and probability in top math journals.

20+ keynote speeches at international conferences (e.g. Germany, France, UK).

20+ research lectures at elite universities (e.g. MIT, Columbia, Berkeley, ETH Zürich).

Taught dozens of math courses at the upper undergraduate and graduate level.

EDUCATION

University of Chicago, Ph.D., Mathematics, 2013.

National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Research Fellowship

Reed College, B.A., Mathematics, 2007.

Phi Beta Kappa, Barry M. Goldwater Scholarship

Contact

Webpage: stromborman.github.io

Email: stromborman@gmail.com

CITIZENSHIP USA